내가 뭐가 문제지?
What is it about me?
Do I not look fun enough?
지루해 보여? 폭탄 같아?
Is there something
repellent about me?
How was the party?
- 파티는 어땠어?
- 최악이었어
It couldn't have been worse.
A woman literally passed through me.
여자들이 날 소 닭 보듯 해
내가 그렇게 매력이 없어?
What is it?
Am I hideously unattractive?
그렇지 않아
내가 보기엔 매력적이야
No, you are not.
You are very attractive.
나도 너처럼 조금만 살이 쪄도
세상이 저주스럽더라
I go through the same thing.
When I put on a little weight,
I question everything.
내가 살이 쪘어?
I've put on weight?
Did you want to...?
- 우리...
- 좋지!
살이 찐 게 아니라
좀 불었다고
No, not weight.
More like insulation.
나 백조 됐는데
네 운동 코치 해줄까?
I'm unemployed,
in dire need of a project.
Wanna work out?
I can remake you.
확실하게 변신시켜 줄게
I would, but that might get
in the way of my lying-around time.
난 빈둥거리는 시간은
포기 못해
Please?
- 부탁해
- 그래, 한번 해봐
Come on, let her do it!
좋아, 좋다고
All right.
If we put on spandex and my boobs
are bigger than yours, I'm going home.
쫄티 입었을 때
내 가슴이 더 크면 관둘래
네 가슴은 괜찮아
내가 괜한 말을 했어
Your boobs are fine.
I shouldn't have said anything.
이리 와
Come here. Come here!
이런, 손이 안 닿아!
Can't make hands meet!
The One Where Ross Finds Out
좋아, 가자고
Let's do it!
What?
왜?
Nothing. Just never seen
your little stretchy pants before.
아냐, 쫄바지 입은 걸
처음 봤거든
And we're changing.
갈아입고 올게
Come on, give me five more!
다섯 개 더!
Five more!
다섯 개!
다섯 개만 더하면
가슴 보여 줄게
Five more and I'll flash you.
One...
하나!
둘!
...two...
...two and a half.
둘 반!
한쪽만 먼저 보여 줘
Just show me one of them.
She's insane!
완전히 돌았어
제 정신 아니라니까!
The woman is insane.
출근 전에, 출근 후에
근무시간에도!
It's before work, after work,
and during work.
She's got me doing
butt-clenches at my desk.
책상에 앉아선
괄약근 조이기를 하래
And now they won't
bring me my mail anymore.
동료들이 변태라고
날 피해 다녀
어서 와, 피비
스캇하고 어떻게 됐어?
Hey, Pheebs.
How'd it go with Scott?
괜찮았어
It was nice. Took him
to a romantic restaurant...
근사한 식당에 가서
샴페인 마시고 좋았어
...ordered champagne. Nice.
He still won't put out?
그런데도 안 넘어가?
응, 완전 돌이야
Nope. Zilch. Nothing.
Sorry, Pheebs.
안됐다, 피비
천천히 해도 괜찮아
난 그 남자 좋거든
Look, I don't mind taking it slow.
I like him a lot.
He's really interesting,
and he's really sweet.
흥미롭고 다정하고...
그런데 왜 안 넘어오지?
Why won't he give it up?
Maybe he drives his car
on the other side of the road.
혹시 우리와는
다른 사람 아닐까?
If you know what I mean.
No. What do you mean?
He's not British.
무슨 뜻이야?
영국사람도 아닌데
게이일지도 모른다고
Maybe he's gay.
아냐, 그건 아닐 거야
I don't think that's the problem.
We went dancing
the other night...
요전에 춤추러 갔는데
...and just the way he held me so close
and looked into my eyes....
날 바짝 껴안고는
내 눈을 들여다보는데
I just definitely felt something.
느낌이 팍 오더라고
표정만 보고 알 수 있어?
But how much can you
tell from a look?
힙도 만졌으니까 확실해
I felt it on my hip.
I could tell.
Yo, Bing!
Racquetball in 20 minutes.
챈들러, 20분 후면
테니스 칠 시간이야
조이, 내 팔로 모니카를
갈겨 줄래?
Joey, be a pal. Lift up my hand
and smack her with it.
레이첼, 보지 마!
Oh, Rachel! Don't look.
뭘?
What?
I don't care.
I have a date tonight.
이제 상관없어
나 밤에 데이트 있거든
데이트가 있어?
You have a date?
그래
모니카가 소개시켜줬어
Monica's setting me up.
- 그럼 로스는...
- 내 시기심 말이야?
What about Ross and....
What? My whole
insane jealousy thing?
그것도 재미있었지만
Well, you know,
as much fun as that was...
이제 정신차리기로 했어
... I've decided to opt for sanity.
You're okay about all this?
정말 괜찮아?
그럼, 당연하지
나도 내 삶을 찾아야지
Oh, yeah, come on!
I'm moving on.
He can press her up against
that window as much as he wants.
창가에 실컷 밀어놓고
키스하라고 해
For all I care, he can throw her
through the damn thing.
창문 깨지면서
넘어갈 정도로 말야
Hi, guys.
- 안녕
- 어서 와
Monica, I'll come by tomorrow and
pick up Fluffy's old cat toys, okay?
내일 플러피 장난감을
가지러 들러도 되지?
이름을 제대로 말하면
If you say his full name.
Can I come over tomorrow and pick up
Fluffy Meowington's cat toys?
플러피 야옹톤의 장난감을
가지러 가도 되겠어?
All right.
그래
-You're getting a cat?
-Actually, we're getting a cat.
- 고양이 기르려고?
- 우리가 함께 키울 거야
함께?
Together?
둘이서? 함께?
Both of you? Together?
로스가 반나절 보고
나머지는 내가 볼 거야
It'll live with Ross half the time
and with me half the time.
참 좋구나
Well, isn't that just lovely?
That's something you'll enjoy...
평생 둘이 아주
알콩달콩 잘 살 거야
...for a really, really,
really long time.
Hopefully.
그럼 좋지
시간이 이렇게 됐네!
난 데이트하러 갈래
Look at that.
I gotta go! I got a date!
남자하고!
With a man.
You guys have a really good night...
다들 즐거운 저녁 보내
둘은 야옹이랑
재밌게 놀고
...and you two have a really good cat.
We're not supposed to
take these when we leave.
참, 이건 두고 가야지
모니카가 말했는지 모르지만
이혼하고 첫 데이트예요
I don't know if Monica told you, but
this my first date since my divorce.
If I seem a little nervous...
좀 긴장돼 보이죠?
사실 그래요
... I am.
고양이가 얼마나 살죠?
How long do cats live?
I'm sorry?
네?
고양이 말이에요
몇 년이나 살죠?
Cats. How long do they live?
Figuring you don't throw them
under a bus or something?
버스에 던지지 않는다면
한 15, 16년이요
Maybe 1 5, 1 6 years.
Well, that's just great.
정말 돌겠네
Cheers!
건배하죠?
그래요, 짠!
Right. Clink.
모니카가 내가 괜찮다고
말했었나 보죠?
Monica told you I was cuter
than this, didn't she?
그게 아녜요, 마이클
미안해요
No, Michael, it's not you.
Sorry. It's just....
신경 쓰이는 게 있는데
사소한 것 같지만
It's this thing.
It's not as bad as it sounds...
... but this friend of mine is
getting a cat with his girlfriend.
친구가 자기 애인하고
고양이를 키운대요
거 정말...
Oh, that does sound....
둘이 사귄지도 얼마
안 됐다고요!
He just started going out with her.
레이첼 옛 애인인가요?
Is this guy an old boyfriend?
Yeah, he wishes.
그 사람 꿈이었죠
I'm sorry. Look at me.
정말 미안해요
이제 당신 얘기나 해요
Michael, let's talk about you.
- 좋아요
- 그래요
So....
애인하고 애완동물
키워 봤어요?
Did you ever get a pet
with a girlfriend?
-So I figured it out.
-What?
- 이유를 알았어
- 뭐?
Why Scott doesn't want
to sleep with me.
왜 스캇이 나와 안 자는지
내가 섹시하지 않아서야
I'm not sexy enough.
Phoebe, that's crazy.
말도 안 돼!
When I first met you,
you know what I said?
내가 널 처음 보고
챈들러에게 뭐라고 했게?
'엉덩이 탱탱하고
가슴 죽이는데'
I said, "Excellent butt, great rack."
정말이야?
고맙기도 해라
Really? That's so sweet.
원래 화가 나야 하지만
그래도 고마워
I mean, I'm officially offended.
But that's so sweet.
정말 그렇게 궁금하면
직접 그에게 물어 봐
If you wanna know what the deal is,
you're gonna have to ask him.
You're right. You're right.
맞아, 그래야겠어
You are so "yum"!
넌 너무 똑똑해!
I mean, it's a cat, you know?
It's a cat.
고양이란 말이에요
고양이!
Why can't they get a bug?
One of those fruit flies.
벌레를 키우면 어디
덧난 대요?
하루 만에 죽는 거 있잖아요
그게 뭐더라...
Those things that live for a day.
What are they called?
Fruit flies?
- 하루살이요?
- 맞아요!
고마워요
Thank you.
- 디저트는 뭐로?
- 됐어요!
Would you like dessert?
계산서나 갖다주세요
부탁해요
No dessert.
Just the check. Please.
Oh, no. You're not
having fun, are you?
재미가 없으시군요
아뇨, 아주 재밌어요
No, no, I am.
자꾸만 고양이가 나오는
공포영화 생각이 나네요
But only because I've been playing
the movie Diner in my head.
내가 왜 이런담
Oh, look at me.
Look at me.
I'm on a date
with a really great guy.
이렇게 좋은 남자하고
데이트하면서
로스, 고양이 생각뿐이라니!
줄리하고!
All I can think about is Ross...
...and his cat...
...and his Julie.
I just want to get over him.
Why can't I do that?
그를 잊어야만 되는데
왜 안 될까요?
난 이혼까지 했어요
좀 지나면 괜찮아져요
Look, I've been through a divorce.
Trust me, you're gonna be fine.
일단 마음을 정리하면
속이 후련해지죠
You can't see it because
you haven't had closure
마음 정리!
Closure!
바로 그거예요!
That's what it is!
That's what I need!
당신 정말 똑똑해!
God, you're brilliant!
왜 진작 생각 못했을까?
어떻게 하면 될까요?
Why didn't I think of that?
How do I get that?
Well, there's no one way
really, it's just....
정해진 방법은 없어요
Whatever it takes so that
you can finally say to him:
어떤 방법을 쓰든지
'널 잊었어'라고 말해야죠
"I'm over you."
Over you.
'널 잊었어'
That's what it is.
바로 그거였어요
마음의 정리...
Closure.
아저씨, 실례해요
Hello? Excuse me?
잠깐... 으악!
Excuse me. Hel
- 잠시만
- 잠시 실례해요
-Hang on.
-Excuse me?
-What?
-Hi. I'm sorry.
- 뭐요?
- 죄송해요
I need to borrow your phone
for just one minute.
전화 잠깐만 빌릴게요
-I'm talking.
-I see that.
- 지금 통화중이잖소
- 알아요
One phone call, I'll be very quick.
I'll even pay for it myself.
잠깐이면 돼요
전화비도 드릴게요
전화기에 너무 집착하시네요
You're being a little weird
about your phone.
All right. Fine.
좋아요
다시 전화할게
I'll call you back.
Thank you.
고마워요
좋아요
응답기예요
Machine.
- '삐' 소리를 기다려요
- 좋아요
-Just waiting for the beep.
-Good.
로스, 나 레이첼이야
Ross! Hi, it's Rachel.
I'm just calling to say that...
전화를 건 이유는
아무 일 없어서야
...everything's fine.
네가 행복하다니 기뻐
네 고양이도!
And I'm really happy for you...
...and your cat.
Who, by the way, I think
you should name Michael.
고양이 이름으로
마이클은 어떨까?
이름이 막 떠오르는데
난 널 잊었어
You see there,
I'm thinking of names...
...so obviously I am over you.
난 널 잊었어!
I am over you.
내 친구 말을 빌리자면
'마음의 정리'란 거라고
And that, my friend,
is what they call "closure."
싫어, 싫어, 싫어!
오늘은 일요일이야
일요일엔 조깅 안 해
It's Sunday morning.
I'm not running on a Sunday.
-Why not?
-Because it's Sunday!
- 왜?
- 일요일이니까!
신을 섬기는 날이라고!
It's God's day.
If you say stop, then we stop.
네가 그만두자고 하면
그만둘게
좋아...
그만둬!
Stop.
No, come on! We can't stop!
지금 포기하면 안 돼!
1.5Kg만 빼면 된다고!
We got three more pounds to go!
I am the energy train
and you are on board!
난 에너지 기차고
넌 승객인 거야!
안녕, 레이첼
데이트는 어땠어?
And how was the date?
레스토랑에 있었어
I think there was a restaurant.
와인도 마셨고
I know there was wine.
줄리가 택시 잡아놨어
고양이 장난감 가져가려고
Actually, Julie's getting a cab.
I just need the cat toys.
Did Monica say....
혹시 모니카가...
왜 그렇게 쳐다봐?
What? Why are you
looking at me like that?
글쎄, 네 꿈을 꾼 것 같은데
뭔지 기억이 나질 않아
I'm sorry. I don't know, l....
I feel like I dreamed
about you last night...
... but I don't remember.
알았어
저기 있구나!
There they are.
어제 우리 통화했어?
Did we speak on the phone?
Did you call me?
No. I stayed at Julie's last night.
아니, 난 줄리 집에서 잤어
I haven't even been home yet.
Do you mind if I check my messages?
집에 안 들어갔는데
메시지 좀 확인해 볼게
그래
Oh, yeah, go ahead.
Rach, I got a message from you!
네가 메시지 남겨놨네
마이클이 누구야?
Who's Michael?
맙소사!
Oh, my God!
Ross, no! Hang up the phone.
Give me the phone!
로스, 당장 전화 끊어
전화기 이리 내!
전화 내놔!
Give me the
날 잊었다고?
You're over me?
Oh, God!
맙소사!
네가... 날 잊었어?
-You're
-Oh, God.
You're over me?
그럼 언제는...
When were you...
... under me?
날 못 잊었어?
레이첼, 혹시...
Rachel, do you...?
그랬던 거야?
I mean, were you?
- 뭐야?
- 알았어, 말할게
What?
솔직히 최근에...
Basically...
...Iately, I've....
널 좋아하게 됐어
I've sort of had feelings for you.
You've had feelings for me?
날 좋아하게 됐다고?
너도 날 좋아했잖아!
So? You had feelings for me first!
You know about my
You know I had
내가 그렇게...
그랬던 걸 알아?
You know?
Chandler told me.
챈들러에게 들었어
챈들러!
언제 그 자식이?
When did he? When did he?
When did he?
- 네가 중국에 갔을 때
- 중국이라...
When you were in China.
- 줄리를 만난 곳
- 줄리라...
Meeting Julie.
Julie. That's
Oh, God!
이걸 어쩌나!
참, 줄리가 있었지
좀 누워야겠어
I need to lie down.
아니, 그냥 서 있을래
No, I'm gonna stand.
I'm gonna stand...
...and I'm gonna walk.
I'm walking and I am standing.
이렇게 서성거리고
지금 난 서 있어!
한데 지금은...
Now you're over me?
날 잊었다고?
Are you over me?
넌 날 잊었니?
줄리일 거야
줄리라고
That's Julie.
-Hi, Julie.
-I've got a cab waiting.
- 안녕, 줄리!
- 택시가 기다리고 있어
금방 내려갈게
I'll be right down!
그렇게 갈 거야?
Wait, so you're going?
그래, 난 가야겠어
Well, okay, I have to.
I can't deal with this right now.
감당할 엄두가 안 나거든
I mean, I've
You know, I've got a cab.
밑에는 택시가 있고
여자친구도 있어
I've got a girlfriend.
I'm gonna go get a cat.
고양이 사러 갈 거야
알았어
고양이!
Cat!
- 안녕, 조이
- 어서 와
-Hey, Joey.
-Hey, Pheebs.
How come you're watching
a rabbi play electric guitar?
왜 랍비가 전기기타를
연주하는 걸 봐?
I can't find the remote.
리모콘이 없어져서
고마워
Thank you.
스캇의 점심초대를
받아서 다녀왔는데
Scott asked me to come over
for lunch and I did.
-And?
-And we did.
- 그리고?
- 했어
잘했어! 축하해!
All right! Way to go!
Yea, me!
알아
So how did it happen?
어떻게 했어?
네가 조언한 대로
솔직하게 물어 봤거든
I took your advice and
asked him what was going on.
뭐래?
What did he say?
여자에겐 성관계가
민감한 사안이라서
He understands how sex can be
a very emotional thing for a woman.
내가 이상하게
생각할까 봐 걱정했대
And he was just afraid
that I was going to get all:
'이 남자가 전화할까?
우리 어떤 관계지?'
"ls he gonna call me the next day?"
and "Where is this going?"
뭐 그런 것 있잖아
그래서 진지해질 때까지
기다렸던 거래
So he said he wanted to hold off
until he was prepared to be serious.
그래서 내가 이랬지
'알았으니 걱정 말아요'
So I said, "Okay. Relax, please."
성관계는 두 남녀의
의지가 맞아야 하잖아
Sex can be just about two people
right there in the moment.
If he wants to see me again, he can
call. If not, that's fine too.
또 만나려면 전화하고
싫으면 말라고 했지
So after a lot of talking...
그렇게 구워삶아서는...
해버렸지
... I convinced him.
잠깐, 정리 좀 하자
Let me get this straight.
네가 섹스하자고 조르고
He got you to beg to sleep with him.
다신 전화하지 않아도
괜찮다고 말하고
He got you to say
he never has to call you again.
이게 좋은 것이라고
생각하게 만들었어?
And he got you thinking
this is a great idea?
응
스승으로 삼아야겠네
This man is my god!
고양이 안 샀어
I didn't get a cat.
That's interesting.
그거...
재밌네
아냐, 재밌는 게 아냐
전혀 재밌지 않다고
No, it's not "interesting."
It's very, very not interesting.
사실 '재밌다'의
100% 정반대라고!
It's actually 100%
the opposite of interesting.
알았어, 로스
I got it, Ross.
왜 내게 날 좋아한다고
말했지?
You had no right to say
you had feelings for me.
뭐라고?
난 그 전까지만 해도
줄리하고 행복했어!
I was doing great with Julie
before I knew!
나도 네가 날 좋아한다는 걸
알기 전에는 행복했어!
I was doing great
before I knew about you!
You think it's easy
to see you with Julie?
너와 줄리의 모습을
보는 게 쉬운 줄 알아?
그럼 줄리를 만나기 전에
진작 말했어야지!
You should've said something before!
그 땐 몰랐어!
그런 넌 왜 말 안 했어?
I didn't know then.
And how come you never said anything?
There was never a good time.
그럴 기회가 없었어
1년 동안 거의 매일 밤
함께 어울렸는데?
You only had a year.
And we only hung out every night!
아냐!
Not...
매일 밤은 아니었어
...every night.
매번 고백을 하려면
훼방꾼이 나타났다고
It's not like I didn't try.
But things got in the way.
이탈리아 애인, 옛 약혼자
또... 다른 이탈리아 남자!
You know, like ltalian guys...
...or ex-fiances...
...or ltalian guys.
이탈리아 남자는 한 명이었어
요점이 뭐야?
There was one ltalian guy, okay?
And do you have a point?
지금은 너무 늦었단 거야!
The point is, I don't need
this right now!
알아들어?
너무 늦었다고
Okay? It's too late.
난 현재로서 행복해
벌써 떠난 배라고!
I'm with somebody else. I'm happy.
This ship has sailed!
그럼 날 향한 감정은
죄다 팽개쳐버렸다고?
You're just gonna put away
your feelings for me?
중학교 때부터 해와서
아주 익숙해졌거든
I've done it since ninth grade.
I'm good at it.
좋아, 맘대로 해라고
All right, fine.
You go ahead and do that.
네 그 조각배는 필요 없어!
I don't need your ship!
- 잘됐네!
- 그래!
-Good.
-Good!
And you know what?
Now I got closure!
하나 더 말해 줄까?
난 마음 정리했어!
아래 고리를 풀어
Try the bottom one.
Monica, it's 6:30 in the morning.
모니카, 새벽 6시 반이야
더 이상 운동 안 해
이제 관둘래
We're not working out.
It's over.
No way! With one pound to go?
Come on!
안 돼, 0.5Kg 남았는데!
우리 신나게, 활기차게
열심히 뛰어 보자!
We're workin', we're movin'
We're in the zone, we're groovin'
그 정도는 안 빼도 돼
I don't mind the last pound.
난 마지막 남은 살을
좋아한단 말이야
In fact, I kind of like the last pound.
내게 후회할 짓 시키지 마
So don't make me do anything
that I'll regret.
What you gonna do, fat boy?
어쩌려고, 뚱보?
왜?
What?
아냐, 네 활기찬 모습이
너무 보기 좋아서
Nothing. Except tell you it's
wonderful how much energy you have.
고마워!
Well, thanks.
직장 잡기도 힘들 텐데
Especially considering how tough
it's been for you to find work.
그거야 뭐...
You can't tell your parents you were
fired, because they'd be disappointed.
해고됐다고 말도 못하고
그래
얼굴을 파묻고
펑펑 울 애인도 없고
It's not as if you have
a boyfriend's shoulder to cry on.
애인은 없지만...
Well, no. But l....
나라면 일어나는 것도
아주 힘들 거야
If it were me, I'd have difficulty
getting out of bed at all.
You know, I try to stay positive.
긍정적으로 살려는 거야
말해 봐
So you....
You feel like going for a run?
아직도 조깅하고 싶어?
응
All right.
억지로 갈 필요는 없어
여기서 자도 괜찮아
Because you don't have to.
You could just take a nap right here.
알았어
잠깐 눈만 붙일게